Ravikant Vasantrao Chobitkar

E-mail: charl.ravikant@gmail.com

Mob: 9082140609

Objective:

Enriching the experience gained over the years by learning additional methods of conducting business and learning new ones; thereby contributing to the growth of the organization.

Summary:

Experience Engineering graduate in sales and marketing professional with an extensive **ready mix** industry exposure of more than 17 years. I have reached a level where I wish to consolidate my experience and exposure. I am looking for a more challenging and rewarding role where I can apply the skills and knowledge I have acquired now.

Brief work profile:

- 1 Worked with RDC concrete as Business Manager (May 2017 to Sep 2022)
- 2 Worked with ACC Concrete Limited, Ready Mix division (JUN2006 to April 2017)
- 3 Worked with L&T ECC division (Ready Mix Concrete) as a Marketing In-Charge at Dahisar Plant in Mumbai from July 2005 to May 2006
- Worked with ACC Cement Division in Nagpur & Akola district technical officer from March 2004 to June 2005.

_ .

Work Experience:

RDC Concrete Limited –(May-2017 to April 2022)

Joined as a Manager Operation in Metro project Plant @ Wadala a Site Based Plant (From May 2017 to Dec2018)

Promoted as Business Manager Mangalore, Karnataka (Jan-2019 to Oct -2021)

Worked as Business Manager site Base Plant @ Shree Cement Navalgarh, Rajasthan

ACC Concrete Limited –(DEC-2010 to April 2017)

- Worked as Sales & Operation In charge Surat (Expand business from one Plant to 3plant in my tenure)
- Plant In-charge from 2010 to Oct 2014. Handling key Project Sales, including Reliance, Isolux(French infra Co.) Essar steel. NTPC, L&T
- · Responsible for EBITA of Surat city
- Handling and monitoring key accounts and maintaining the daily sales outstanding report

Key Achievement:-

(Develop business in the Industrial segment and won Reliance Order of 2lac cum in 2014)

(A loss-making unit after 2010 is in a profitable cost center)

Work in sales - PUNE (Hinjewadi Plant) from 2009 to 2010

- Hardcore Concrete sales and marketing
- · Complaints handling and resolution with the QC team
- Regular customer follow-up and feedback to improve quality and service
- Realization of payments and collections as per the monthly targets.

Work as Logistic officer from 2008 to 2009 (Mumbai)

- Worked in the Customer Service Dept as a distribution and service in charge for Mumbai region.
- Responsible for planning and scheduling of concrete pours for on time delivery .
- Cost control by optimizing the use of resources like transit mixtures and concrete pump

KEY Achievement

(Increase utilization of resources by 12%)

(Reduce Cost by 4%)

Work in Businesses Development from 2006 to 2008

- Analysis for business growth in respective city
- All Statutory clearances and NOCs for setting up a unit from respective Government Authorities including Municipal Corporation, Pollution control, Health Dept, NHAI, etc.
- All execution work related matter.
- Survey for proper land for setting unit.
- Planning and scheduling of all the activities within a certain time frame.

KEY Achievement

(Ready mix plant executed with 42 day @ Lodha Belessimo ,N.M.Joshi Marg ,South Mumbai)

Larsen & Toubro ECC division - Read Mix Concrete Unit, Mumbai as Marketing in Charge (Dahisar Plant) from July 2005 to May 2006.

- Joined as Assistant Engineer in Marketing Division and was promoted to Marketing In charge in October 2005.
- · Hard core Concrete sales and marketing.
- Responsible for achieving the monthly sales target.
- Complaints handling and resolution.
- Providing consulting services and support for and quality of concrete to customers.
- Regular customer follow up and feedback to improve quality and services.
- Realization of payments and collections as per the monthly targets.

Winner of best plant (Dahisar plant) in India at L&T RMC for 2005-06 for overall performance.

ACC (Associate Cement Company Limited) as Technical Representative in a customer service department from March 2004 to June 2005.

- Handling retailers and dealers in Nagpur and Akola districts.
- Appointing new dealers and retailers in the 2 districts.
- Conducting masons, contractors and engineers meet.
- Organizing architects meet with the CSD manager.

Academic Qualifications:

Exam	Year	University/Board	Percentage	Division
	Passed	omversity/Board	rercentage	
BE - Civil	2003	Nagpur University, Nagpur	56%	II
HSC	1996	Pune Divisional Board, Pune	68%	I
SSC	1994	Nagpur Divisional Board, Nagpur	64%	I

Executives -MBA in Marketing (distance lerning)

Computer Skills : Ms-office, SAP.

PERSONAL DETAILS:-

Name : Ravikant Vasantrao Chobitkar

Date of Birth : 15/08/1978

Gender : Male

Nationality : Indian

Marital Status : Married

Languages Known : English, Marathi & Hindi

Permanent Address : B-502, Shrinidhi, Kothwa coloney, Lohegaon

Pune-411047

Correspondence Address B-502, Shrinidhi, Kothwa coloney, Lohegaon

Pune-411047